http://probinso.dyn-o-saur.com

#### Personal Statement

I am presently a graduate student at Oregon Health and Sciences University. After completing my BS at Western Washington University, and my 4 years industry expirience, I have developed strong interests in cryptography, statistical computing, and languages. I am a very quick study, as I have adopted a new programming language or tool-set in nearly every challenge I have taken on. My interest in teaching and writing has granted me strong communication skills, and solid background.

## Language Experience :

\* Python Julia Scala, Figaro Perl Ada C, C++, C#  $\mathbb{E}T_EX$ 

# Education \_

# Oregon Health Science University

CSLU Non-Matriculated (Masters)

2016 - present

#### Courses :

\* Machine Learning Analysis of Sequences

★ Information Retrieval Univariate Statistical Analysis

\* Ethics of Machine Learning Statistical Methods

## Western Washington University

Computer Science

Computer Science BS Mathematics Minor Sept. 2007 - June 2012

### Courses :

Unix Software Development Formal Languages/Automata Windows Software Development Programming Languages Analysis/Design of Algorithms Concurrent Programming Linear/Non-Linear Data Structures Computer Organization I/II

#### Elective Courses :

Homomorphic Encryption Systems Computer Architecture Cryptography & Elliptic Curves Number Theory Artificial Intelligence Elementary Real Analysis Natural Language Processing Ordinary Differential Equations Functional Programming Linear Algebra I/II Computer Graphics Abstract Algebra

## Honors and Related Activities

Comap Mathematical Modeling Competition (Meritorious Winner) - Top 10% - Feb. 2012 Comap Mathematical Modeling Competition (Honorable Mention) - Top 30% - Feb. 2011

# Neato Projects

Gradient Descent on Arbitrary Degree Polynomials Julia Gene Data Breast Cancer Drug Predictor R, caret Sensor Systems and Light Pollution Course aws, sklearn, scipy, PonyORM, Python Distributed Fully Homomorphic Encryption System Hadoop, Python Concurrent Elliptic Curve Cryptography Module Erlang, Sagemath Analysis of Subordinating and Coordinating Conjunctions R, Perl AdaRailz Concurrent Model Train Control System Ada Java TwixT AI Agent and UI Fractal Art Generator & Image Manipulation Program C#

# Work Experience

### Independent

#### - Contractor/Consultant

C&W Energy

Nov. 2015 - present

Authored educational material on light pollution's effect on economy, biology, and technology Light classification engine, custom photo image processing tools, and mathematical models Developed a memoizing database-interface for caching computationally expensive operations

ComScore June 2016 - Sept. 2016

Worked to support large, custom, memory mapped, data store for demographic analysis

PDXCodeGuild June 2016

Developed and taught introductory python course material for coding boot-camp

Melinae March 2016

Setup infrastructure in AWS to enable secure sustainable workflow for remote company Provided hands on training in Python and R to industry professionals

Languages Used: Python, R, AWS, PostgreSQL, Perl, C++

# Galois Inc. - Research Engineer

April 2014 - Dec 2015

Contributed to PPAML, Overseas Voting Foundation, Safeware, Robot Fast Track
Developed technologies and workflows to enable evaluator work for DARPA programs
Produced biannual quantitative and qualitative reports on for DARPA and language developers
Participated in programs sharing new technologies to research and industry professionals

Languages Used: Python, Scala, Figaro, Chimpy, Docker

 ${\tt EMC}^2$  Isilon Storage - Software Development Engineer Dec. 2012 - July 2013

Brought to schedule a lagging anchor release feature in approximately 5 months Designed and developed password manager to support Data At Rest Encryption Wrote unit tests using libcheck to attain > 80% code coverage

Languages Used : C, C++, Python, SQLite

Computer Science Dept. - Mentors Program Director/Mentor Sept. 2009 - March 2012

Provided safe environment for training and instruction of students and mentors Ran student/faculty meetings to project future program responsibilities
Wrote comprehensive quarterly reports, and tools for automatic report generation

Languages Used: Ada, C++, Scheme, R